<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/GUI/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/GUI/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/Hymnology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/Hymnology/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/Operating-Systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/Operating-Systems/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Election-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Election-Notes/</guid><description>A Republican Form of Government Not party-related, literal definition We get to choose who&amp;rsquo;s in charge Legislative Elections We elect House Reps every 2 years The Parties are Dying!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Executive-and-Congress-Study-Guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Executive-and-Congress-Study-Guide/</guid><description>Things to Do: Look over representatives video EOP and the Cabinet Big Three Review Sheet</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Executive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Executive/</guid><description>Between the Georges (Washington - Bush) Hail to the Chief Why do people want to be President Vision Ego They have to (see Washington) Lots of people hate the President Presidency is difficult, cut them some slack Washington (1789-1796) Legitimacy of the Presidency Father of the Country Has to wrangle a country of rebels back into law-abiding citizens Must enforce things like paying taxes Really good dancer Good horse-rider Good legs Residual Powers (inherent powers) Washington was the first to expand his power through this to quench the Whiskey Rebellion &amp;ldquo;I greatly fear that my countrymen will expect too much from me&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Jefferson (1800-1808) Federalist vs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Gov-Review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Gov-Review/</guid><description>Key Words – POLS 1787 American national Government Test Two – Two of Three Branches quizlet
Key Words Current Info (2023) Current Representative and Senators for Searcy (names) Tom Cotton and John Boozman (Senators) French Hill (Representatives) Current Presiding Officers (names) Speaker of the House: Kevin McCarthy (R) Presiding Officer: VP (Harris) Pro Tempore: Patty Murray (D) Maj Leader of Senate: Charles Schumer (D) Min Leader of Senate: McConnell (R) Maj House: Steve Scalise (R) Min House: Hakeem Jeffries (D)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Judicial-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Judicial-Notes/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s on the docket right now? Delaware v. Penn/Wisconsin MoneyGram Haaland v. Brackeen Indian Child Welfare Merrill v.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Pressure-and-Influence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Pressure-and-Influence/</guid><description>Pressure: Persuading/intimidating/influencing someone to do something</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Social-Justice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Social-Justice/</guid><description>w</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Supreme-Court/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Supreme-Court/</guid><description>Current Members (2023) Ketanji Brown Jackson (D nom) Amy Coney Barrett (R nom) Brett Kavanaugh (R nom) Samuel Alito (R nom) John Roberts (Chief Justice) (R nom) Neil Gorsuch (R nom) Sonia Sotomayor (D nom) Elana Kagan (D nom) Clarence Thomas (R nom) The Song (Jesus Loves Me) Jackson, Barrett, Kavanaugh,</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Voting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Voting/</guid><description>Turnout Getting better, but not great still from 2014 to 2018 student voting rates double&amp;hellip; from 20% to 40%. Variation from State to State States choose how they want to do elections Sec.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/</guid><description>q&amp;mdash; title: Software Engineering enableToc: false enableLinkPreview: true OOSE Notes Software Engineering Exam 1 Study Guide Software Engineering Exam 2 Study Guide Scrum Scrum An Intro to Agile Product Backlog Software Engineering Sprint Review Retrospective</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/An-Intro-to-Agile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/An-Intro-to-Agile/</guid><description>The Waterfall has many offshoot techniques One is the UP, from that comes Agile, from which comes Scrum One Wasatch (Snowbird Ski Resort) A group of developers (many of which were from competing companies) got together to formulate ideas on how to make software engineering better Wrote the Manifesto for Agile Software Development 4 values Individuals and interactions over processes and tools working software over comprehensive documentation Customer collaboration over contract negotiation Responding to change over following a plan The italic is important, but the bold is more important Purposes of Agile Large projects Continuous use (can prevent down-time for maintenance/further development) Knowledge of what is going on Business side awareness/Transparency Predictability Easy updating Quality User focused About Kanban Use what you already have Incrementally advance what you can Respect previous development Encourage leadership 12 Principles of Agile Satisfy the Customer</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Estimation-and-Velocity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Estimation-and-Velocity/</guid><description>What are Estimation and Velocity? Estimation: guessing how much work there is left to do Velocity: how fasts the team is doing work By dividing the work left by how fast the work is done allows for a calculation of how long it is going to take Three types of Estimation Portfolio backlog Product backlog Sprint backlog Estimation Concepts Estimate as a team Value accuracy over precision Estimates are not commitments Use relative size estimates Estimation Units Story Points vs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Abstract-Data-Types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Abstract-Data-Types/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Cohesion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Cohesion/</guid><description>Cohesion Myers&amp;rsquo; 7 levels of Cohesion (adapted by Schach) From bad to good:
Coincidental Cohesion (worst) Logical Cohesion Temporal Cohesion Procedural Cohesion Communicational Cohesion Functional Cohesion Informational Cohesion (best) 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Coupling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Coupling/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Data-Encapsulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Data-Encapsulation/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Information-Hiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Information-Hiding/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Inheritance-Polymorphism-and-Dynamic-Binding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Inheritance-Polymorphism-and-Dynamic-Binding/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Objects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/Objects/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/The-Object-Oriented-Paradigm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/The-Object-Oriented-Paradigm/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/What-is-a-Module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-7/What-is-a-Module/</guid><description>What is a Module? A Thorough Definition &amp;ldquo;A lexically contiguous sequence of program statements, bounded by boundary elements, having an aggregate identifier&amp;rdquo; What the heck does that mean?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Product-Backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Product-Backlog/</guid><description>What is the Product Backlog? A prioritized list of desired product functionality Heart of the Scrum framework Product Backlog Items (PBI) Visualized in a queue data structure Items included are: Features User stories Use cases Free form text Defects Technical Work Knowledge acquisition D.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Retrospective/</guid><description>What is it? Examining the process after each sprint (Process Review) Allows teams to customize Scrum Improve the process mid-product 3 questions: What worked?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Scrum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Scrum/</guid><description>What is Scrum? Scrum is an agile process framework Scrum is not an acronym, but a reference to rugby where the players lock arms and struggle for possession of the ball Comprised of time-boxed sprints (called iterations) At the end of each sprint, there is a potentially shippable product (aka, likely new version) Where to use Scrum Complicated projects where adaptation to change is required often When Not to use Scrum Simple problems, or chaotic problems Main Features Product Backlog Sprint Planning Sprint execution Daily Scrum Sprint Review Sprint Retrospective Members of the Scrum Team Product Owner Responsible for the quality of the product (managerial leader) Development Team Responsible for implementing the product Scrum Master Responsible for managing the product (technical leader) Product Backlog List of known features that need to be added to a product Usually ordered by important Sprint Planning Product owner and development team agree on sprint goal Planning which items from the product backlog to work on during the sprint Important to set an attainable pace Sprint Execution Actual construction &amp;ldquo;Done done&amp;rdquo;: actually done A high degree of confidence in the sprint&amp;rsquo;s product Daily Scrum Timeboxed, usually about 15 minutes Inspect and adapt Standup meetings Three Questions What did I accomplish since the last daily scrum?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Software-Engineering-Exam-2-Study-Guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Software-Engineering-Exam-2-Study-Guide/</guid><description>From Schach, chapter 11 What three things must be specified in the specification document? 2. Functional Requirements 3. Constraints 4. Acceptance Criteria List the steps of the analysis workflow, as given in the book and augmented in class.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Execution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Execution/</guid><description>Overview Sprint execution is like a &amp;ldquo;mini-project&amp;rdquo; Takes up most of a sprint (up to around 75% of it) Participants Team, Scrum Master, and Product Owner answer clarifying questions Process Execution starts with the goal and the backlog, and ends with a potentially shippable product Remember that the goal of Scrum is to have a potentially shippable product at the end of every sprint Flow Management Dev team must manage the flow of work during execution to meet the goal, includes Parallel work Task Performance Dev team members need to be skilled in good technical practices for Scrum to work Many good practices come from Agile/Extreme Test-driven Refactoring Pair-programming Continuous Integration Collective code ownership Automated testing Communication Easier in a short timebox with a small team (like in a sprint) Task Board + Sprint Burndown/Burnup charts are used [[Sprint Review]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Planning/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Sprint-Review/</guid><description>What is it? 2nd to last phase Provides clear, transparent look at the current state of the project Allows for input from all Scrum parties Prework Determine who to invite, what each person is presenting, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/To-whom-does-the-power-of-salvation-belong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/To-whom-does-the-power-of-salvation-belong/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Amos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Amos/</guid><description>Intro Amos the Man Profession Shepherd (7:14) Dresser of Sycamore Trees (7:14) Volunteer Prophet (untrained) Geography/Setting Native of South Judah (1:1-2) Prophesied in North Israel (In the days of King Uzziah) Messages International Judgement (1-2) Social Justice (2:6, 3:1, 4:1-5) Restorative discipline (4:6-12) Acceptable worship (5:5, 14-15, 21-24) Salvation through judgement (9:7, 11-15) New Testament Quotations of Amos Stephen&amp;rsquo;s speech: Israel rejects God and his prophets James&amp;rsquo; speech: Gentile Christians are fulfilled God of the Nations Discusses 8 nations (1-2) Damascus Philistia Tyre Edom Ammon Moab Judah Israel Amos talks about how they will all be destroyed by God for their sins Bethel and Gilgal Wives of the Israelites called &amp;ldquo;Cows of Bashan&amp;rdquo; Pampered and prized They oppress the poor through indifference/demanding more wealth Prophecy of the Assyrian exile with fishhooks Note: Inaction is oppression.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Daniel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Daniel/</guid><description>Theme: New Kingdom Historical Context Nebuchadnezzar exiled Judah in 3 waves 605 BC (Jehoiakim) 597 BC (Jehoiachin) 586 BC (Zedekiah) Daniel, Hananiah (Shadrach), Mishael (Mishach), and Azariah (Abednego) exiled in 605 Rose in power in 6th century BC under Nebuchadnezzar, Belshazzar, Darius the Mede, and Cyrus of Persia Book Structure Chapter 1-6 Court narrative of Daniel and Friends in Bab-Persian exile Unclean diet 1st dream interpreted Fiery furnace 2nd dream interpreted Handwriting on Wall Daniel in the Lion&amp;rsquo;s Den Chapters 7-12 Daniel&amp;rsquo;s Apocalyptic visions of the Coming Kingdom of god 4 beasts, ancient of days Son of Man Ram and Goat Abomination of Desolation Angels of Nations at War Time, Times, and 1/2 Time Purposes Daniel was revered as a hero by the exiles Inter-testamental books praise wisdom and cunning Bel and the Dragon Susanna Be faithful unto martyrdom!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Exam-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Exam-3/</guid><description>Q1: The Prophets &amp;amp; Their Day: Your friend sends you a YouTube video about how prophets in the OT only predicted the distant future.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Ezekiel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Ezekiel/</guid><description>Theme: New Life
Ezekiel in Babylonian Exile 592 BC Mentally travels back to Judah through visions/dreams Talks a lot about complacency Who are the Righteous/Remnant?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Haggai-and-Zechariah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Haggai-and-Zechariah/</guid><description>Haggai see notes Consider your Ways (Schedule) Current Schedule Schedule with God Prioritized 8 Class Whatever God wills 9 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 10 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 11 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 12 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 1 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 2 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 3 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 4 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 5 Homework Whatever God wills 6 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 7 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 8 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills 9 :obs_down_arrow_with_tail: Whatever God wills Zechariah [[Daniel]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Hosea-Part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Hosea-Part-2/</guid><description>Faithfulness: A study in Hosea Chapters 4-5 &amp;ldquo;Divorce Proceedings&amp;rdquo; Reev: Covenant Lawsuit Reason for Divorce: No relational knowledge No one wants to be with God (they swear, lie, murder, steal, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Isaiah-1-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Isaiah-1-3/</guid><description>Israel&amp;rsquo;s Estranged Herself from God Israel is under divine judgement (Ahab&amp;rsquo;s House) 3 Sins: Forsaken God Hypocritical worship Corrupt society Israel does not &amp;ldquo;know&amp;rdquo; God (1:3-9, 5:13, 1:21) They know how to &amp;ldquo;worship&amp;rdquo; God, but they do not actually know Him Providence did not lead to gratitude Forsaken the Holy One of Israel (this phrase is used 25 times) Shows that God is distinct, different from the other &amp;ldquo;gods&amp;rdquo; Utterly estranged, beyond remedy Nearly extinct as a nation God Seeks After the Estranged God seeks sincere worship and sincere lives (1:10-17, 29) God rejects manipulative and syncretistic worship God seeks transformed lives and worship God will purify Israel by exile (1:18-29, 25-26, 31) Gentiles will flow into Israel (2:1-5) [[notes/Spring 2023/Wisdom and Prophets/Isaiah 6]]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Isaiah-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Isaiah-6/</guid><description>Israel&amp;rsquo;s Call Models Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s Call God is Israel&amp;rsquo;s Living King (6:1) Highest of All (6:2-3) Israel is unholy compared to God (6:4-5) God purifies Isaiah with Fire (6:6-7) Scriptural theme of Fire (sometimes leading fire like in the wilderness, sometimes cleansing/destructive fire like Sodom/Gomorrah) Heavenly council calls for messenger (6:8) Preach until no one listens (6:9-13) What on Earth are you Here For?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jeremiah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jeremiah/</guid><description>Theme: &amp;ldquo;A New Covenant&amp;rdquo;
7 Facts About The Man Born into a priestly family/town who later oppose him Called to prophesy &amp;ldquo;too young&amp;rdquo; According to Jeremiah, he needed help to speak well Prophesied the fall of Jerusalem (his own city), from Josiah to Zedekiah (627-586 BC) &amp;ldquo;The Weeping Prophet&amp;rdquo;: Loved his people and his country Likely wrote Lamentations Called to celibacy as a sign of YHWH&amp;rsquo;s irrevocable decision to punish his people Persecuted heavily Whipped, put in stocks, accused of treason/sedition/desertion, plotted against, imprisoned in cisterns and courtyards, stoned in Egypt and left for dead Speaks &amp;ldquo;jeremiads&amp;rdquo; (imprecatory psalms) 7 Facts About The World Josiah was 21 years old (627 BC) Josiah discovers &amp;ldquo;The Book of the Law&amp;rdquo; (622 BC) Either the Pentateuch or just Deuteronomy Josiah reforms Jerusalem before his premature death in 609 BC Egypt, Assyria(:obs_down_arrow_with_tail:), and Babylon (:obs_up_arrow_with_tail:) fight over Palestine Jeremiah says Babylon is God&amp;rsquo;s agent, but Zedekiah allies with Egypt Jerusalem is besieged in 586, and Zedekiah does not give up the fight as Jeremiah advised When Governor Gedaliah is killed, Jeremiah and Baruch are taken by the murderers to Egypt 4 Facts About The Book Longest book in the OT (longer than book of 12 combined) Loose collection of oracles - poetic with some prose Jeremiah dictated chapters 1-35 to Baruch (scribe) (36:4) There are multiple books of Jeremiah today: First edition burned by Jehoiakim (36:23) Hebrew Jeremiah: longer than 35 chapters (36:32) Greek Jeremiah: 6/7ths the length of the Hebrew and the OAN (Oracles of the Nations) are in a different order and location The DSS confirm at least 2 Jeremiahs, the Hebrew and Greek (4QJera,b,c) (4th Cave at Qumran) Minor difference between them, just inclusion of specific oracles 7 Sign Acts (not comprehensive) Linen belt in rock crevice = ruined/useless (13:1-11) Moisture ruins the fabric Bought jug and smashed it = city &amp;amp; people (19) Made/wore a yoke = Nebuchadnezzar (27:1-15) Hananiah (false prophet) broke the yoke to contradict Jeremiah (28) Buys a field = exile will be temporary (32:6-15) Throws scroll in sea = Babylon will sink (51:59-64) Buries stones in Egypt = Babylonian throne/conquest (43:8-13) No funeral/feast = no time because of exile (16:5-9) Survey of Key Chapters 1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/jeremiha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/jeremiha/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jobs-Misery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jobs-Misery/</guid><description>Job&amp;rsquo;s Friends Eliphaz: God Follows Retribution Retribution revealed by the natural order and the divine Human should respond with repentance/appreciation Divine should restore the repentant Bildad: God is Just Does God prevent justice?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jonah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Jonah/</guid><description>Intro An experienced prophet (2 Kings 14:25) Probably a real person From Gath-Hepher The Storm at Sea (Ch. 1) Typical prophetic call, atypical response Cry out against implies a possibility of repentance (Jonah probably knows this) Three times &amp;ldquo;down&amp;rdquo; to Joppa/into the boat/into the sea God sends his word, a storm, a fish, a plant, a worm, and an east wind The Pagan mariners are more faithful than Jonah Jonah&amp;rsquo;s Lament Psalm (Ch.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Lamentations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Lamentations/</guid><description>Context Emotional poem about the fall of Jerusalem Date: 586 BC, the fall of Jerusalem Genre: ___ lament Overview Author: among &amp;ldquo;the writings&amp;rdquo; in Hebrew, but associated with Jeremiah in the Greek Purpose: Theodicy and Healing Theodicy: God was behind this!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Malachi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Malachi/</guid><description>Prophet and Date Malachi = &amp;ldquo;My Messenger&amp;rdquo; Date: Persian Period (520-460 BC) Problems of the era: Careless priests Skepticism about the Messiah&amp;rsquo;s coming Intermarriage with pagans Edom recently destroyed The overall question: If the exile is over, where then is the golden age of Israel that the prophets promised?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Micah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Micah/</guid><description>Theme: Walking with God Many mentions of walking in the book Introduction 8th Century Prophet (750-700 BC) Denounces wealthy who oppress the poor Alternating oracles of warning and hope Micah translates to &amp;ldquo;Who is like YHWH&amp;rdquo;?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Prophets-and-Prophecy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Prophets-and-Prophecy/</guid><description>The Function of a Prophet To intercede for God and Man To call people back to God To offer a second chance To demonstrate justice/grace the Prophets and Their Literature Early prophets: Abraham Moses Elijah Elisha Nathan Latter prophets: Isaiah-Malachi Major (Isaiah-Dan) and Minor (Hosea-Malachi) Delineation based on book length Minor often called the &amp;ldquo;Book of the 12&amp;rdquo; Pre-Exilic, Exilic, and Post-Exilic Categories overlap depending on which exile (Assyrian and Babylonian) you&amp;rsquo;re looking at Ex.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Song-of-Solomon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Song-of-Solomon/</guid><description>Structure Conversing about love (Ch 1) Female lover (2-3) Male lover (4) Female lover (5) Male lover (6) Female lover (7) Conversing about love (8) Rabbi Aquiva Songs of Solomon is the Holy of Holies Origen Forbade any Christian under 30 to read it as it would be seen as mere love poetry.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-3rd-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-3rd-copy/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-4th-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-4th-copy/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-another-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-another-copy/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/temp1-copy/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/To-whom-does-the-power-of-salvation-belong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/To-whom-does-the-power-of-salvation-belong/</guid><description>Who are you finding it difficult to forgive? Will you forgive them? I had an ex who I had known for the majority of my life.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Waiting-for-the-Lord/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Waiting-for-the-Lord/</guid><description>The most important decision I have to make is what to do with openly associating with Christians, despite the fact that many Christians behave in a very unchristian manner.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/What-on-Earth-are-you-Here-For/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/What-on-Earth-are-you-Here-For/</guid><description>Mission before college I often gave technological help to the church in any way that I could. I once worked on a need request form that use some Google plugins to automatically mail people capable of doing the task at hand.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Culture/</guid><description>What Is Culture? Shared values that aid in communication Cultures often don&amp;rsquo;t align on many things Societies have their own individualized coping mechanisms for the challenges of the world How Can We Interact With Cultures?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Gods-Purpose-in-History/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Gods-Purpose-in-History/</guid><description>Goals of this Lesson To demonstrate God&amp;rsquo;s overarching Plan to save the nations through the people of Israel To encourage us to actively take part in Missio Dei Biblical-historical sketch Passages Matthew 1:1 Psalms 110 w/ Matthew 22:41-46 and 1 Corinthians 15:24-28 Ephesians 1:3-14 - God&amp;rsquo;s purpose Galatians 3:14 - Our purpose Christ&amp;rsquo;s Vision for the Spread of the Gospel Acts 1:8-10 Beginnings in Acts Jerusalem To Samaria (Because of persecution) Missionary journeys of Paul and his companions Spread of Christianity Jerusalem Base of activity for the 12 apostles Although Jerusalem eventually loses the role of HQ, she retains prominence in the movement Syrian Antioch (Acts 13-14; 15-21) The first multi-cultural church Becomes the first sending church in Christianity Rome Hints in Book of Romans (16) In time becomes the center of Western Christianity Constantinople After the division of Roman Empire, Const is now the center of activity Becomes center for Eastern (Orthodox) Christianity By Orthodox believers, still considered the mother church &amp;ldquo;Nestorian&amp;rdquo; or Church of the East Nestorius (386-451) Archbishop of Constantinople 428-431 Involved with controversy of Theotokos eventually condemned for heresy at the Council of Ephesus in 431 Churches East of Syrian Antioch were called &amp;ldquo;Nestorian&amp;rdquo; by Western Churches Baghdad becomes center of missionary activity for the East They were very active in the 10/40 window Main Points from 10/40 The original 1990 GIS 10/40 Windows analysis produced several insights, among them showing that the nations of the 10/40 Window represents 82% of the poorest of the world&amp;rsquo;s poor 84% of those with lowest quality of life (life expectancy, infant mortality, and literacy) The hub of the world&amp;rsquo;s major non-Christian religions (Islam, Buddhism, Hinduism, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/I-wish-the-Bible-had-been-more-clear-about.../</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/I-wish-the-Bible-had-been-more-clear-about.../</guid><description>Dinosaurs LBGTQ+ issues Women in the Church Instruments in the Church Chapel vs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Islam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Islam/</guid><description>Ramon Llull 1232-1315 Converted at 30 years old Muslim in the Modern Era Muslim is growing all over the world Arabs are not Muslims necessarily This is in the same way that Americans are not Christians necessarily Arab Christians/Jews exist Shia are roughly similar to Catholics and Sunni are roughly similar to Protestants (in methodology) Iranians are known as Persians not Arabs Another term for Persian is Farsi Arabs are Semites, meaning they speak a Semitic Language Semitism more literally means &amp;ldquo;descending from Shem&amp;rdquo; In addition, both Jews and Arabs descend from Abraham (Jews from Issac, Arabs from Ishmael) 90% of Muslims are Sunni Indonesia has the largest Muslim population in the world Iraq is mostly Shia Muslims Iran is Shia (and not Arab) Palestine is Sunni and Arab The Quran and Jesus Commonalities Virgin birth through Mary He was given the Gospel to preach Jesus (not Muhammad) will come to judge the world Differences in the Quran from the Bible Jesus was not the Son of God Ascended to Heaven Points of Contact with Muslims Belief in One God Belief in God&amp;rsquo;s Judgement Common points between Quran and Bible Remember to be loving and respectful (1 Peter 3:15) Be willing to admit our own inconsistencies and weaknesses Travis&amp;rsquo; C-Scale C1-C6 scale High-risk to low-risk God&amp;rsquo;s Purpose in History</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jonathan-Stricklyn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jonathan-Stricklyn/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Kellers-3-Points/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Kellers-3-Points/</guid><description>Faithful Presence Within The Reference Point for Evaluating Culture Evaluate based on God&amp;rsquo;s Holiness (not based on your culture) Note the response of those who catch a glimpse of God&amp;rsquo;s glory (Isaiah 6:5; Luke 5:8; Rev 4:8) The challenge of being &amp;ldquo;in the world&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;of the world&amp;rdquo; Jesus is the Perfect Model The Word (Logos) became Flesh (sarx) He became like us in every way, but without sin He was in the world, but not of the world He warned us, do not be surprised of the world hates you The Mantra of the World Christian 1 Corinthians 9:19-23 Be like them so as to see from their perspective and win them over through interpersonal Christlike love Extremely important for outreach NT Case Studies in Culture John 4: Jesus and the Samaritan Woman Unusual because Jesus is talking intellectually not only to a Samaritan, but to a Samaritan woman Acts 10: Peter and Cornelius Unusual because Peter is in the house of a Roman Acts 15: The Jerusalem Conference The contextualization of the gospel message throughout Acts (13, 14, 17) The World Christian and Culture God is supra-cultural by nature I would say exo-cultural, meaning outside of it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Origin-of-Our-Diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Origin-of-Our-Diversity/</guid><description>The Natural Way of Things Creation is &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; Unity = &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; Sin/Rebellion = shame as a natural response This shame/sin/rebellion results in violence Languages There is no documented &amp;ldquo;mother language&amp;rdquo; This is because of the abrupt death of that language during the Tower of Babel incident Tower of Babel story suggests that diversity&amp;rsquo;s origin was from rebellion and sinful pride resulting from human unity(?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Jeremy-and-Martha-Smith/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Jeremy-and-Martha-Smith/</guid><description>Mozambique 20 years in Mozambique Southeast Africa Only flag with an AK-47 on it Portuguese is the main language 40 other African languages spoken Smiths spoke mostly Makua Suffering from the effects of 30 years of war One of the poorest countries in the world (Smiths&amp;rsquo; guess is #7) Things that missionaries into Mozambique have to take into account People of Mozambique don&amp;rsquo;t know who they can trust (American-bred civil war) Americans are inherently untrustworthy as super rich and the ones who tore their country apart Way of Life Houses made from wood/bamboo/mud with a bit of plastic for water resistance Common food is shima (white porridge) Bit of meat (usually chicken) No running water, trips to a well are required Missionaries have to wear a lot of hats Details 6 couples on the outgoing original team (2004) Started with a lot of pride (&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re gonna save Mozambique!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/The-Cost-of-Being-a-World-Christian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/The-Cost-of-Being-a-World-Christian/</guid><description>Main point: self-awareness/sacrifice is essential to the faith Why is this Hard? The &amp;ldquo;cost&amp;rdquo; is not stressed in our preaching and teaching It does not sit well with our worldly values of freedom and independence The idea of &amp;ldquo;cost&amp;rdquo; has been misused No one likes to be made to feel like they are not doing enough, or stated positively, we all liked to be praised After having the discussion, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to fall into &amp;ldquo;judging mode&amp;rdquo; What this lesson is Not A discussion of the way of salvation We are saved by grace through faith.</description></item><item><title>1.1</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.1/</guid><description>Historical Aspects 1967: NATO study group coins term software engineering Claim: Building software is similar to other engineering tasks The Software Crisis Software quality was unacceptably low Deadlines/budgets were not being met Terrible because software is expensive to build Statistics: 18% cancelled 53% completed late/overbudget/missing features 29% success 78% of IT organizations have &amp;ldquo;been involved in disuptes that ended in litigation&amp;rdquo; 67% of those cases were because of poorly functioning/performing products 56% of those cases were because of shifting deadlines 45% of those cases were so severe that the product was unusable</description></item><item><title>1.2</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.2/</guid><description>Economic Aspects Essentially, coding is such a small percentage of the time/cost that if a new coding technique can be produced 10% than an old one, it is still often more profitable to use the old method because of the time/money cost of learning the new technique</description></item><item><title>1.3</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.3/</guid><description>Maintenance Aspects Life-Cycle Model A description of steps to take when building a software product Model is broken into phases, the number of which vary between models Life-Cycle Steps from concept to retirement of a product Until late 70&amp;rsquo;s Waterfall was the leading model 6 phases: Requirements phase Concept exploration/refinement Analysis (specification) phase Requirements are broken down into specifications, a plan is drawn up Design phase 2 design processes Architectural Design Product is broken down into modules Detailed Design Each module is broken down into more specific instruction/specifications These processes result in design documents.</description></item><item><title>1.4</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.4/</guid><description>Requirements, Analysis, and Design Aspects content</description></item><item><title>American Government</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/</guid><description> [[American Symbology]] [[Political Science]] [[The Constitution]] Constitution Study Guide [[Laws]] Branches [[Congress]] Executive No judicial notes Executive and Congress Study Guide Voting Just kidding turns out there actually were Judicial Notes Election Notes Social Justice Pressure and Influence [[]]</description></item><item><title>American Symbology</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/American-Symbology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/American-Symbology/</guid><description>What we choose to represent us to the rest of the world
Common Symbols E Pluribus Unum Out of many, one Bald Eagle They go wherever they want (represents freedom) Personal note: can also represent hubris/pushiness/predatorial Log Cabin Made of wilderness Built from nothing Represents adaptability Also represents pushing the frontier Sometimes at the cost of others Uncle Sam Wants you to join the military Represents American strength/military Occasionally represents &amp;ldquo;friendliness&amp;rdquo; (as much as can come from the military) Liberty Bell Broken bell because we rang it too much after winning the Revolutionary War We keep it as a symbol of our love for liberty Statue of Liberty Gift from France Symbol of immigration Inscription: Give me your tired, your poor, Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free,</description></item><item><title>Chapter 1</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/</guid><description>Introduction to Object Oriented Software Engineering [[OOSE 1.1|1.1: Historical Aspects]] [[OOSE 1.2|1.2: Economic Aspects]] [[OOSE 1.3|1.3: Maintenance Aspects]] [[OOSE 1.</description></item><item><title>Class Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/</guid><description>Daily Notes The Holy Spirit Matthew 3 Jesus&amp;rsquo; Humanity Jesus and the Holy Spirit First Verse Memorization The Work of the Spirit in Acts The Work of the Spirit in the Epistles Worldview Truth Culture Keller&amp;rsquo;s 3 Points Islam God&amp;rsquo;s Purpose in History The Origin of Our Diversity The Cost of Being a (World) Christian Visiting Speakers Louis Bassay Jeremy and Martha Smith</description></item><item><title>Congress</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Congress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Congress/</guid><description>OUR legislative branch They work for us! How a Bill becomes a Law Same bill has to pass the house and the senate, then it is approved by the President Bill must be introduced by a member of Congress Bill Drafting makes sure the language is perfectly detailed Committee reports bill out to another committee or to one of the two Houses Bill is then placed on a calendar (list of bills to be read and voted on) House Rules Committee sets the rules for consideration 1 hour is indicative of a big decision, and is the maximum allocated time Filibustering is a thing that exists, and it&amp;rsquo;s stupid Conference committee works out the differences between the bills passed by HOR and Senate President then can sign it or veto it If it is vetoed, the it returns to the house of origin and the process restarts Or there can be a veto override, but with a partisan government, no way.</description></item><item><title>Constitution Study Guide</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Constitution-Study-Guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Constitution-Study-Guide/</guid><description>Word Pairs Power/Authority Power = Strength, Authority = right Issues/Politics Laswell&amp;rsquo;s/Lenin&amp;rsquo;s definition of politics Laswell = authority, Lenin = power Cost/Benefit Not always monetary or immediate How to value prevention?</description></item><item><title>Cross-Cultural Experiences</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Louis-Bassay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Louis-Bassay/</guid><description>Louis Bassay About From Cameroon VBS for 1 month Destroyed Brazil in soccer Prayers: Civil War in Cameroon Household Code in Cameroon Husband and Wife To become a woman&amp;rsquo;s husband, the man must bring the woman&amp;rsquo;s family many items in order to earn her (this is known as a &amp;ldquo;bride price&amp;rdquo;) All women must be able to cook, and the men don&amp;rsquo;t cook Appearance in public Not particular, but affection is shown Parent and Children Appellation The young must call the old with respect (Uncle/Aunt/Daddy/Momma) Eye Contact Disrespectful to look directly in the eyes of an elder Verbal expression of love Never expressed verbally, but it is showed in other ways Social Responsibilities Greetings Very important, greetings must be expressly spoken and reciprocated, especially to elders Time Event-oriented, not time-oriented &amp;ldquo;White-man time&amp;rdquo; refers to time-oriented as opposed to event-oriented The guest closes the conversation Invitation The host pays the bill</description></item><item><title>Ecclesiastes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Ecclesiastes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Ecclesiastes/</guid><description>Theme: Carpe Diem Question: &amp;ldquo;Is there meaning in life?&amp;rdquo;
Hevel: Meaningless
General Viewpoint of the Author They were a king They gather that everything is meaningless (Eccl.</description></item><item><title>Exam 1 Study Guide</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Software-Engineering-Exam-1-Study-Guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/Software-Engineering-Exam-1-Study-Guide/</guid><description>Define Software Engineering. A good definition is this one from Wikipedia: “The discipline of software engineering encompasses knowledge, tools, and methods for defining software requirements, and performing software design, software construction, software testing, and software maintenance tasks.</description></item><item><title>Fall 2023</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Fall-2023/</guid><description>Subject List: Operating Systems Hymnology GUI</description></item><item><title>First Verse Memorization</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Memory-Work/First-Verse-Memorization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Memory-Work/First-Verse-Memorization/</guid><description>have faith in me, and you will have life-giving water flowing from deep inside you, just as the Scriptures say. Jesus was talking about the Holy Spirit, who would be given to everyone that had faith in him.</description></item><item><title>How to Raise a Fool</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/How-to-Raise-a-Fool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/How-to-Raise-a-Fool/</guid><description>Who is the Fool? Faulty definitions Inept but lucky Gullible yet sincere Blundering but lovable Under this definition, &amp;ldquo;foolishness&amp;rdquo; is not a tragic flaw or sin A true fool fails to appreciate the concern of the wise and the warning of Jesus Becoming this kind of fool is a subtle, four-stage process Stage 1: Isolated Acts of Folly Everyone starts off as a simple/naive child Potential for both wisdom and folly are possible Isolated acts of Folly: Easily angered (14:17) Self-trusting Fighter (20:3) Reckless Undependable (26:6) Doesn&amp;rsquo;t care Quickly consuming income (21:20) Lacks focus Incessant Talking (12:23; 17:28) Failing to control speech Parents are responsible for preventing this To raise a fool, do nothing Teaching a child grants them wisdom Stage 2: Folly as Sport Disregarding discipline Repeating foolish behavior Enjoying folly Stage 3: Beyond Correction Hates the idea of knowledge 2 Factors Thinks they&amp;rsquo;re right Always takes the path of least resistance (fast money, short-term gain, etc.</description></item><item><title>Isaiah</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Intro-to-Isaiah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Intro-to-Isaiah/</guid><description>Theme: New Creation Intro: Isaiah&amp;rsquo;s name means &amp;ldquo;YHWH is Salvation&amp;rdquo; One of the Four Major Prophets Dead Sea Scroll (1QIsa, first scroll of Isaiah at Qumran) Almost complete 2nd c.</description></item><item><title>Jesus and the Holy Spirit</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jesus-and-the-Holy-Spirit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jesus-and-the-Holy-Spirit/</guid><description>Luke 4 Led by the Spirit into the wilderness to be tempted (1-2) Returned in the power of the Spirit to Galilee (14-15) Regarded as nothing more than &amp;ldquo;Joseph&amp;rsquo;s son&amp;rdquo; Generally well liked, but not regarded as the Son of God John 3 How Jesus speaks to others about the Spirit Note: Pharisees were persecuted by the Romans for being too radical Nicodemus respected and learned from Jesus Decided to give Jesus a proper burial despite the view of his peers Calls out his peers as they give Jesus an unfair trial to save their skin Discussion with Jesus about being born again Water vs Spirit Spirit/WaterFleshSpirit-SpiritFlesh-Flesh Note: Sometimes it is impossible to baptize someone before death, but sometimes it is difficult but possible, in which case an attempt might be made John 10 Zoe : Real (eternal, genuine) life Bios : Biological/Physical life Bios mirrors Zoe, but in the same way that a picture or statue mirrors a person A man is naturally a creation, not a descendant, of God A man can have his Bios end, but continue through Zoe, which is obtained through the rebirth of baptism according to the Christian Faith Essentially, living only in Bios is being a dead man walking Our Responsibility Are we an Undertaker or a Mid-wife?</description></item><item><title>Jesus' Humanity</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jesus-Humanity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Jesus-Humanity/</guid><description>John 1 &amp;ldquo;Word&amp;rdquo;: logos/dao logos is a word with undefined meaning, John &amp;ldquo;baptizes&amp;rdquo; the word (gives it a holy meaning) John 1:1 outlines the Trinity In the beginning was the Word&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Laws</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Laws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Laws/</guid><description>Three types of Laws Constitutional Statutory Common/Judge Made &amp;ldquo;Kindergarten&amp;rdquo; rules Precedent: What happened previously is important Judges follow previous decisions Judges can overturn rulings if necessary Stare Decisis: Standing on decided cases The powers given to the judicial branch in Article III are&amp;hellip; tiny.</description></item><item><title>Matthew 3</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Matthew-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Matthew-3/</guid><description>Analogies Verse 11 I baptize you with water for repentance. But after me comes one who is more powerful than I, whose sandals I am not worthy to carry.</description></item><item><title>Memory Work</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Memory-Work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Memory-Work/</guid><description>First Verse Memorization Note: most of my memorization has been done orally, rather than on paper/type. The way in which memorization works best for me is by recalling chunks of the verse, then slowly beginning to string those chunks together into a full verse/set of verses.</description></item><item><title>Object Oriented Software Engineering Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Notes/</guid><description> [[OOSE Chapter 1|Chapter 1: Introduction to Object Oriented Software Engineering]] Chapter 7: From Modules to Objects</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.10</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.10/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.11</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.11/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.5</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.5/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.6</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.6/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.7</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.7/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.8</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.8/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>OOSE 1.9</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Software-Engineering/OOSE-Chapter-1/OOSE-1.9/</guid><description> content</description></item><item><title>Political Science</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Political-Science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/Political-Science/</guid><description>The study of those relationships involving power and authority, especially those including government
From the Text Issues: A conflict, real or apparent, between the interests, ideas, or beliefs of different citizens Politics: The activity by which an issue is agitated or settled Cost: A burden that people believe they must bear if a policy is adopted Note: This is more than just monetary cost Benefit: A satisfaction that people believe they will enjoy of a policy is adopted Definitions Politics Who gets what, when and how According to Lenin, &amp;ldquo;who could do what to whom&amp;rdquo; Power Possession of control over others Politics is the pursuit and exercise of power From the text: &amp;ldquo;The ability of one person to get another person to act in accordance with the first person&amp;rsquo;s intentions&amp;rdquo; The ability to influence another&amp;rsquo;s behavior Power, like money, is a means to other ends Democracy Rule by the people Derived from Greek words $demos$ (the people) and $kratos$ (authority) Made the framers nervous (implies mob rule) Writings of &amp;ldquo;Publius&amp;rdquo; Dangerous, turbulent, chaotic Direct and Indirect Democracy Direct is akin to mob rule Indirect is akin to a Republic Greek&amp;rsquo;s three legitimate governments Monarchy Could turn to despotism Aristocracy Could turn to oligarchy Democracy Could turn to mob rule They did not accept tyranny With very small amounts of people, Limited Direct Democracy is acceptable People are directly able to execute: Initiative Referendum Recall Republic Form of government where the governed have sovereignty and power, but that power is channeled through representatives who run the government Ability to vote for the representatives is given to the citizens This form of government is guaranteed in the US Government People/institutions/processes in which rules are made and where power to enforce them is possessed Regulates the use of legitimate force (see authority) Authority ^7d6965 The right to use power &amp;ldquo;Legitimate&amp;rdquo; power &amp;ldquo;Leg&amp;rdquo; prefix is in legal, legislative, legible, etc.</description></item><item><title>Reading Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/</guid><description> Week 1 Week 2 Week 3 Week 4 Week 5 Week 6</description></item><item><title>Spring 2023</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/</guid><description>Subject List: World Christian Wisdom and Prophets American Government Software Engineering</description></item><item><title>The Constitution</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/The-Constitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/American-Government/The-Constitution/</guid><description>Issues Small States and Large States Small States wanted equal representation Large States wanted proportional representation This resulted in two legislative houses (House of Reps for proportional, Senate for equal) Federalists vs Anti-Federalists How Strong is too Strong?</description></item><item><title>The Holy Spirit</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Holy-Spirit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Holy-Spirit/</guid><description>Goal To emphasize the Holy Spirit and his work as the driving force in both transforming and bringing good news to the world Holy Spirit and Kingdom Empowerment through the Holy Spirit (Acts 5:32) Condition for being an apostle was to have been with Jesus (Acts 4:13) Important because the apostles were otherwise unremarkable The Holy Spirit will come to the disciples and transform them (Acts 2) It would be dangerous for them to go out before the Spirit is upon them because it would be their words, not God&amp;rsquo;s They are even told to go into Samaria to deliver the Gospel Jesus and the Holy Spirit</description></item><item><title>The Work of the Spirit in Acts</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Work-of-the-Spirit-in-Acts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Work-of-the-Spirit-in-Acts/</guid><description>He loves Thee too little, who lives anything together with Thee, which he loves not for thy sake
Augustine of Hippo</description></item><item><title>The Work of the Spirit in the Epistles</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Work-of-the-Spirit-in-the-Epistles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/The-Work-of-the-Spirit-in-the-Epistles/</guid><description>Romans 5 Not just forgiven by God, but also loved by God Therefore, we can rejoice in suffering for Him First Adam doomed us all, Second Adam (Jesus) saved us all Choose a lineage Romans 7 Faith is like marriage One husband Bound by law Cheating is bad Man&amp;rsquo;s nature is to break laws and go against God Paul says, &amp;ldquo;For what I want to do I do not do, but what I hate I do.</description></item><item><title>Top 15 College Proverbs</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Top-15-College-Proverbs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Top-15-College-Proverbs/</guid><description>Topics Sleep Proverbs 20:13 and 3:21-24 Lesson and Meaning: If you have done well during the day, you&amp;rsquo;ll sleep better.</description></item><item><title>Truth</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Truth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Truth/</guid><description>What is Truth? $\alpha \lambda \epsilon \theta \epsilon \iota \alpha$ (Aletheia) in Greek Aristotle: Metaphysics 1011b “to say of what is that it is, and of what is not that it is not, is true.</description></item><item><title>Types of Psalms</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Types-of-Psalms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Types-of-Psalms/</guid><description>Penitential Laments Structure Address to God Complaint Request Expression of Faith Takeaways These types of Psalms are about not accepting &amp;ldquo;cheap grace&amp;rdquo; It is an acknowledgement of sin, and an acceptance of responsibility You cannot forgive your own sins, this must be taken up to God Trying to regain God&amp;rsquo;s favor and do his work God&amp;rsquo;s grace is not &amp;ldquo;cheap&amp;rdquo;, but it is still given plentifully Imprecatory Psalms Psalms that ask God to bring curses upon enemies Goals include: Cursing Individuals Cursing Nations Divine Judgement Religious persecution Liberation for God&amp;rsquo;s Name&amp;rsquo;s Sake etc.</description></item><item><title>Week 1 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-1/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Living God is a Missionary God&amp;rdquo; - Scott Types of Fulfillment Progressive Fulfillment Fulfillment of past, present, and future Past Life of the nation of Israel Present Immediate/Gospel fulfillment in Christ/the Church Future Eschatological/Ultimate fulfillment (new heaven/earth) All based on the Composite Promise to Abraham (posterity, land, and blessing) Immediate Historical Fulfillment Fulfillment to the people of Israel Posterity Descendants of Israel are plentiful Land Israel taking The Promised Land Note: Land was never fully inherited by direct descendants of Abraham Blessing Extended to &amp;ldquo;all families on earth&amp;rdquo; Israel is a &amp;ldquo;light to the nations&amp;rdquo; Intermediate Gospel Fulfillment Fulfillment to Christ and His Church Posterity Spiritual descendants of Abraham includes the Gentiles Land Because of Spiritual inheritance of Abraham&amp;rsquo;s blessing, there can be children of Abraham all over the world, allowing Abraham to &amp;ldquo;inherit the world&amp;rdquo; (Rom 4:13) Blessing The blessing is salvation from one&amp;rsquo;s sins for any who accept the inheritance Ultimate Fulfillment Ultimate or eschatological fulfillment in the final destiny of the redeemed All descendants (physical and spiritual) of Abraham will enjoy the privilege of being before the throne of God in heaven Conclusion God of History God has control over history/events God of the Covenant God keeps his promises God of Blessing God gives positive reinforcement God of Mercy God gives second chances God of Mission God wants us to spread Christianity throughout the world &amp;ldquo;Blessing as Transformation&amp;rdquo; - Gallagher &amp;amp; Hawthorne Summary God works with/through His People Uses the skills of his people to do great things Increase and Fullness, but never perfection Perfection is impossible God focused society can thrive and flourish Growth, not redistribution Dispersal $\neq$ spreading Blessings from the Poor/Powerless God works with weakness Blessing can be slow-forming and long-lasting Variability in timing Blessings give a sense of obligation, transforming the Christian into a servant for God &amp;ldquo;Witness to the World&amp;rdquo; - Bosch The &amp;ldquo;Servant of The Lord&amp;rdquo; As Christians we should be fully devoted to the Lord Avoid having one foot in paganism and another in Christianity God and Man as Competitors The wills of God and Man naturally oppose each other We should strive towards aligning ourselves with God&amp;rsquo;s will Centripetal vs.</description></item><item><title>Week 2 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-2/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Master&amp;rsquo;s Plan&amp;rdquo; - Coleman content &amp;ldquo;Beyond Loving the World&amp;rdquo; - Bryant content &amp;ldquo;Life on Purpose&amp;rdquo; - Hickman, Hawthorne &amp;amp; Ahrend content &amp;ldquo;Culture, Worldview and Contextualization&amp;rdquo; - Kraft content Week 3</description></item><item><title>Week 3 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-3/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Bible in World Evangelization&amp;rdquo; - Stott content &amp;ldquo;Lost&amp;rdquo; - McQuilkin content &amp;ldquo;Understanding Culture&amp;rdquo; - Kwast content &amp;ldquo;The Flaw of the Excluded Middle&amp;rdquo; - Hiebert content Week 4</description></item><item><title>Week 4 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-4/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Do Missionaries Destroy Culture&amp;rdquo; - Richardson content &amp;ldquo;Finding a Place and Serving Movements Within Society&amp;rdquo; - Hiebert content &amp;ldquo;The Difference Bonding Makes&amp;rdquo; - The Brewsters content Week 5</description></item><item><title>Week 5 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-5/</guid><description>“Going Too Far?” – Parshall “Must all Muslims Leave “Islam” To Follow Jesus? – John J. Travis “Insider Movements” – Rebecca Lewis “On Mission With God” – Blackaby &amp;amp; Willis “A History of Transformation” – Pierson “The Social Impact of Christian Missions” – Robert D.</description></item><item><title>Week 6 Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Reading-Notes/Week-6/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;State of the World Need&amp;rdquo; - World Relief  &amp;ldquo;Let the Nations Be Glad!&amp;rdquo; - Piper  &amp;ldquo;Cities and Salt, Counter-Cultures for the Common Good&amp;rdquo; - Keller &amp;ldquo;Discipling All The Peoples&amp;rdquo; - Piper Back to main</description></item><item><title>Why Is All of This Happening? Sources of Evil and the Christian's Response</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Sources-of-Evil-and-the-Christians-Response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Sources-of-Evil-and-the-Christians-Response/</guid><description>Why Is All of This Happening? Sources of Evil and the Christian&amp;rsquo;s Response Who is Responsible for Evil? Rāh in Hebrew is &amp;ldquo;hardship&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;trouble&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;disaster&amp;rdquo; God brings about both good and rāh (trouble) Where does evil come from?</description></item><item><title>Wisdom and Prophets</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/</guid><description>Wisdom Wisdom Literature Types of Psalms How to Raise a Fool Top 15 College Proverbs Job&amp;rsquo;s Misery Sources of Evil and the Christian&amp;rsquo;s Response Ecclesiastes Song of Solomon Prophets Prophets and Prophecy Amos Hosea: Faithfulness Isaiah: YHWH is Salvation Jonah Micah Jeremiah Ezekiel Daniel Daniel</description></item><item><title>Wisdom Literature</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Wisdom-Literature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/Wisdom-and-Prophets/Wisdom-Literature/</guid><description>3 Books Proverbs Job Ecclesiastes Context General truths (Proverbs 26:4-5) Observations about the world What is the wise thing to do given a situation?</description></item><item><title>World Christian Notes</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/</guid><description> Class Notes Reading Notes Memory Work</description></item><item><title>Worldview</title><link>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Worldview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agsup.github.io/quartz/notes/Spring-2023/World-Christian/Class-Notes/Worldview/</guid><description>About America America was never perfect (still isn&amp;rsquo;t, it sucks) Harding&amp;rsquo;s view is also imperfect Peter Fisherman to Apostle Confessor of Christ Instrument of Satan to Witness of the Resurrection Bold leader Ethnocentric to Christocentric Worldview completely transformed Paul Destroyer of the church to builder Persecutor to persecuted Pharisee to Apostle Defender of the law to champion of grace Characteristics of Metamorphosis Encounter with the Christ They had to face their prejudices and false presuppositions of the world Born again by the Spirit Became &amp;ldquo;radicals&amp;rdquo; in promoting Christ Definition of Worldview The fundamental cognitive, effective, and evaluative presuppositions a group of people make about the nature of things, and which they use to order their lives</description></item></channel></rss>